In the last lecture, we created our saga generator here and it doesn't look too useful right now,
Son derste destan retecimizi burada oluturduk ve u anda ok kullanl
well we need to hook it up to our store.
grnmyor, bu yzden maazamza balamamz gerekiyor.
Now to do that, we need to go to the place where we create our store in the index.js file and there, I
imdi bunu yapmak iin, maazamz indekste oluturduumuz yere gitmeliyiz. js dosyas ve imdi, ben sadece
now don't just want to create the store,
maaza yaratmak istemiyorum, bunun
I instead want to also register my sagas and make sure that these are kind of something my store is
yerine sagalarm da kaydettirmek ve bunlarn maazamn farknda olduu ve
aware of and can use. For that, I need to import something else, I will import create saga middleware from
kullanabilecei bir ey olduundan emin olmak istiyorum. Bunun iin baka bir eyi ie aktarmam gerekiyor, ben de redux destanndan destan
redux saga, like this and I will also import something else, I will import the saga I just created, before
ara katmanlar ithal edeceim, bunun gibi ve baka bir eyi de ithal edeceim, daha nce yarattm destan, bundan nce
that in my auth.js file in the sagas folder,
auth'umda ithal edeceim. sagas klasrnde js
I'll add an export keyword in front of my generator function and save the file.
dosyas, jeneratr fonksiyonunun nne bir ihracat anahtar szc ekleyeceim ve dosyay kaydedeceim.
So back in the index.js, I can then import my logout saga here from ./storeSagas auth.js
Yani endekste geri. js, daha sonra kmn adn buradan alabilirim. / storeSagas auth. js ve isimlendirmeyle tutarl
and to be consistent with the naming,
olmak iin,
I'll actually go back in to the auth.js file in the sagas folder and name this logoutSaga as
aslnda auth'a geri dneceim. js dosyas sagas klasrnde ve bu logoutSaga'y bir jeneratr ad
a generator name and therefore I'll also import this name,
olarak adlandrr ve bu yzden bu ismi de alrm, bu istee
this is optional but it also makes clear what this is. Now with that imported, what we can do,
baldr, ancak bunun ne olduunu da akla kavuturur. imdi, bu ithal, ne yapabiliriz,
we can also execute the create saga middleware function, store the result in a constant, so I'll name the constant
biz de efsane middleware fonksiyonu yrtmek, sonu sabit bir saklayabilirsiniz, bylece ben sabit sagaMiddleware
sagaMiddleware and then execute create sagaMiddleware, just like that without any arguments
adn ve daha sonra herhangi bir argman olmadan ve imdi olduu gibi sagaMiddleware oluturmak icra biz maaza oluturmak, burada
and now when we create the store, I'm calling applyMiddleware here and there
applyMiddleware aryorum ve orada sadece thunk middleware uygulamak deil, ayn
I don't just want to apply the thunk middleware but also my saga middleware
zamanda benim destan middleware uygulamak istiyorum ben bu yzden
so I will add it as an argument to applyMiddleware.
applyMiddleware bir argman olarak ekleyelim.
Finally after all of that, I can use my sagaMiddleware which is also registered in the store and
Sonunda, maazada da kaytl olan sagaMiddleware'i kullanabilirim ve burada bir destan
there, I can run a saga
altrabilirim, bu yzden
so here I can run my logout saga which we also imported in this file, right. Now with that, if I save all
burada bu dosyaya da aktardmz k logosunu altrabilirim. imdi, eer hepsini kurtarrsam ve bavurumuza
of that and we go back to our application and we reload it,
geri dnersek tekrar yklersek, burada muhteem bir ey
well we see nothing spectacular here, do we?
grmyoruz, deil mi?
Let's go into our redux dev tools and there we see something interesting,
Redux dev aralarmza gidelim ve orada ilgin bir ey
we see that logout was executed here a couple of times,
gryoruz, kn birka kez gerekletirildiini gryoruz, imdi
now that makes sense because in our auth action creator, we actually also dispatched the logout action in
bu mantkldr nk bizim auth eylem yaratcmzda, aslnda aslnda checkout eylemimizdeki k
our check state action where we try to auto login the user
eylemini de gnderdik Geerli bir belirte
if we don't find a valid token. Now for testing purposes, let's comment out all logout dispatches,
bulamazsak otomatik olarak kullanc girii yapmaya alrz. imdi test amal olarak, tm oturum kapatma gnderilerini
so if we save this file and we go back to our application, if we now reload this application, we still
yorumlayalm. Bu dosyay kaydedersek ve uygulamamza geri dnersek, imdi bu
see that auth logout was dispatched and that is coming from our saga,
uygulamay yeniden yklersek, hala outh knn gnderildiini ve bu
as I can prove that they go to the index.js file and I comment out this sagaMiddleware, run logout saga
durumun destanmzdan geldiini grrz. Dizine gittiklerini kantlayabilirim. js dosyas ve ben bu sagaMiddleware, ben k destan satrn altrn
line.
yorum.
If I do that and I go back and now I reload the page, you no longer see that being dispatched.
Bunu yaparsam geri dnyorum ve imdi sayfay yeniden yklyorum, artk gnderilmediini gryorsun.
So we seem to do something with our saga,
Bu yzden destanmzla bir eyler yapyor gibi grnyoruz, hep
we're always calling it so
yle diyoruz, bu yzden yorum
let me comment in all the things we commented out because always calling this saga doesn't look too
yaptmz her eye yorum vermeme izin verin nk her zaman bu destan armak pek kullanl grnmyor,
useful, does it? Right now,
deil mi? u anda,
right at the start when we built the application, when we started, we run our logout saga which despite
uygulamay balattmz ilk anda, baladmzda, bu garip jeneratrler bir ey
this strange generator stuff going on simply does one thing, it removes all these items from local storage
yapmasna ramen, tm bu eleri yerel depolama biriminden kaldrr
and dispatches the auth logout action.
ve yetkilendirme eylemini gnderir.
Obviously we don't want to run this at application start up,
Akas bu uygulamay balatmak iin
instead we do want to run this code in the place where we previously ran our logout action creator,
altrmak istemiyoruz, bunun yerine bu kodu, daha nce kullandmz oturum eylemi yaratcmzn
where we used this,
bulunduu yerde
so the goal has to be that we actually dispatch an action to which we can listen with
altrmay istiyoruz, bu yzden ama aslnda bir eylemin
redux saga so that our saga generator can run once the action is recognized.
tannmas iin destan retecimizin alabilmesi iin redux destanyla dinleyebileceimiz eylem.
Let's work on this in the next lecture.
Bir sonraki derste bunun zerine alalm.